Summary

James is responsible for driving the advancement of Contino's technical team members, who provide top-tier professional services and systems integration to both domestic and international customers. With a strong background in DevOps methodologies and toolsets, he leads innovation and product development to ensure that Contino maintains leadership in the market while effectively supporting its growth strategies and initiatives—all of which are powered by Contino's diverse and global engineering team. With over 10 years of experience in Defense, Diplomatic and NGO technology sectors across 12 countries, James brings a unique range of experiences that are well-suited to Contino's market solutions.

Work Experience

Contino - Director of Sales APAC Sydney, AUS- June 2017 - Present

- Performed DevOps/Engineering workshops for multiple clients
- Created, scoped and designed extremely technical material for banking and financial services clients. Subjects of import include helping Australian FIS organisations prepare for Data Breach Notification Laws, more rapidly responding to ASIC/APRA/AUSTRAC inquests and request for information, and protecting the security and soveriegnety of Australian Data.
- Created custom compliance and reporting code based on the Australian Signals
 Directorate Information Security Manual.
- Created custom code for client projects.

<u>Levvel - VP of Technology 2016 - 2017 - Sydney, AUS</u>

- Led expansion into APAC market
- Opened first 3 accounts for Levvel APAC, with major corporate clients (ANZ, Prudential & Cathay Pacific) in New Zealand, Singapore and Hong Kong.
- Managed and added key technology partnerships to increase channel sales opportunities
- Built a high-performance team through effective hiring, coaching, and growth & development
- Implemented durable and scalable processes, tools, and automation
- Drove planning, budget development and strategic priorities, working within the engineering leadership team to shape and execute operations strategy and objectives
- Drove development and execution of technology infrastructure initiatives and optimize current infrastructure and support systems

 Collaborate with executive leadership and other business groups to increase effectiveness of operations projects, programs and communications

Levvel - DevOps Practice Lead 2013 - 2016

Wells Fargo

- Led a 10 person DevOps team administering a multi-datacenter Puppet installation.
- Defined a regulatory and compliance framework to increase bank security using configuration management and SEC reporting requirements.
- Wrote custom Puppet modules
- Abstracted multiple services into the greater DevOps pipeline
- Integrated with multiple WF services, networks and datastores using custom Puppet modules.

Internet2

Ported multiple applications into custom Dockerized applications.

- Developed custom deployment strategy using Docker Compose.
- Created custom scripts for sourcing and writing user-specific data before runtime.
- Wrote custom Ansible/Vagrant scripts to automate building of VM environments for end-users who were not comfortable with executing raw Docker commands.
- Developed a distributed, federated identity server in a Docker container.

Branch Banking & Trust

- Conducted on-site training of Chef fundamental skills. Coordinated architectural design for migration of 500+ servers into Chef's management and configuration system.
 Authored multiple Chef cookbooks for company specific installations of technologies like Java, tcServer, and DB2.
- Deployed within VMWare vRealize Suite, using Jenkins, Gerrit, Docker, Chef, RSpec and Artifactory for artifact management.
- Enforced 100% testing requirements using ChefSpec, ServerSpec and syntax checkers.
- Wrote control groups and audits based on the popular CIS audit cookbook.

Spireon

- Reviewed Redis deployment and made infrastructure, architecture, and software development recommendations for a high-volume GPS application using Redis for in-memory caching.
- Resiliency testing and failure simulation between master and slave nodes to develop and test operational procedures for failover and certification of recovery process.
- Code changes that resulted in 5x improvement in performance for adding cached objects to lists.
- Kernel parameter tuning that improved memory allocation performance.
- Infrastructure and architecture changes to create a chained slave deployment to allow for multi-site redundancy

QuietStream Financial

 Designed and implemented medium-sized Hadoop cluster in AWS for ETL jobs related to financial services Performed resiliency testing and failure simulation between master and slave nodes to develop and test operational procedures for failover and certification of recovery process

<u>Triple Canopy - Senior Technical Consultant 2012 - 2013</u>

- Led the solution design for Ruby based software projects supporting Defense logistics and supply chain services.
- Advised US DoD and ISAF (International Security Assistance Force) on best practices for structuring and maintaining ETL application.
- Scoped, designed, and led software implementation projects from analysis and requirements gathering, through to development, testing and deployment.
- Participated in on-call rotations, Level 1,2 & 3, technical support and failure scenario / disaster recovery drills.

<u>United States Marine Corp January 2002 - January 2006</u>

• Provided security research, training, coordination and logistical support for numerous <u>US</u> <u>Embassies</u> in sub-Saharan Africa.

Technical Blog Posts

https://www.linkedin.com/in/denmanjd/recent-activity/posts/

Skills

O/S: Linux, Windows, OSX, RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu,

AmazonLinux

Languages: Ruby/Rails, Shell, Java, HTML/CSS, JavaScript/JQuery

Database: SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, NoSQL

Solutions: Chef, Ansible, Docker, AWS, Redis, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, OpenShift

Certifications: Docker Authorized Consulting/Training Partner, ElasticSearch Operations

Education

University of North Carolina - Charlotte, Charlotte, North Carolina 2007-2011

B.A. International Relations, B.A. French Language

Galvanize University, Denver, Colorado

Backend Software Engineering, Computer Science